Uh, first of all, I don't believe a word
he says about uh being in contact with
the CIA. If anybody at the CIA were in
contact with him, they would have to
report it immediately. You have 24 hours
to report contact with an UN uh cleared
person. So, I think he's making that up.
When it comes to the FBI though, you
know, any slob can roll out of bed and
log on to fbi.gov and fill out a report
that's going to be ignored for the next
hundred years. I strongly suspect that
he's inflating this to make it look like
he's doing something or is somebody that
he's not. And I'll I'll tell you exactly
why.
>> I uh I had knowledge of a major fraud
involving more than $100 million. I
literally could not get an appointment
with the FBI. The reason I wanted to
report it was because I stumbled into it
and I didn't want to be involved with
it. I couldn't get an appointment with
the FBI. Finally, I contacted a former
deputy director of the FBI to tell him
he got me the appointment at the FBI. In
the first 10 seconds that I was there,
the FBI agent put up his hand and said,
"Buddy, if this doesn't include the
words terrorism, Russia, or China, we're
not interested." And that was the end of
the meeting.
>> So, I mean, confidential informant is a
term of art in the FBI. So, if the FBI
calls him or calls anybody and and he
answers their questions, he dishes out
dirt.
>> That's it. Is is he is he a confidential
for informant or is he just an informant
or is there a distinction that
>> Yeah, he's a confidential informant
which you and I I think would call a
rat, right?
>> If the FBI is looking for somebody just
to rat people out, they'll call and say,
"Hey, do you have anything for me?" And
he says, "Oh, James O'Keefe, he's he's
not a good guy. He's a bad guy. What can
you give me on James O'Keefe?" "Oh, he
overspent on Ubers."
>> Right?
>> So, he's acting as a that's a
confidential
>> enforcement. And and if he and if he
embellishes to the FBI or uses
hyperbole, he spent $2 million on
private jets, which is untrue. That's
he's still an informant. He's just
informing
>> and committing a felony,
>> which is a crime to lie to the FBI.
>> That's right. It's a crime to lie to the
FBI.
>> Um we have another clip here on the
SDNY. This is this is I'm feeding the
SDNY tons of [__] Let's play this clip
from
>> I've got him right on so much fraud.
I've already fed the Southern District
tons of shell. I've got more. Yeah.
>> And I'm one of I'm not special. I don't
think I'm a little special. But he's a
[__] scumbag.
>> That's why I fed the Southern District
tons of [__] to try.
>> So the people ask questions right SDNY,
which I interpret the SDNY, which is a
very interesting Do you know anything
about the SDNY?
>> I do.
>> It's it's called the Sovereign District
of New York. People are asking questions
about that. One of the questions I
always have, are they referring to the
prosecutors or the FBI in that district
or both?
both, I think, but a little more so the
prosecutors. The Southern District of
New York is where prosecutors,
especially junior prosecutors, go to
make a life for themselves. Every one of
these guys sees himself one day as the
US attorney, as a member of Congress,
running for governor or in that corner
office in an A-list uh law firm. They go
there to make their bones so they can
start making the big money or initiate a
political career.
>> So, it's ambition.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. And it's going to be on
your back and my back and anybody else
that they can destroy.
The incentives are so reversed, aren't
they? The incentives. We'll get to
accountability in a bit. Um, one more
clip here. This is this is a question we
got asked a lot after we released the
stories going viral as I sit here with
you right now. millions of views, but
everyone's asking me the same question,
which is why would he do this or why
does someone you say rat, I call I call
it a rat as well. Why would someone do
this? And and um we're going to play
this clip and we're going to ask you
what you think it means. This is guys
clip 104. I had phone calls from DOJ
sources telling us that telling me that
I was on an enemy's list under the B
administration.
Last year ahead of the election I had
phone calls from DOJ sources telling me
that I was on a enemy's list that was
going to get purple off.
>> Is that like a threat or they were
warning you? Like
>> they were warning. I had a friend who
happened to be at the DOJ at a deputy
level
>> who called me and said on a Friday night
at midnight and said like, "Dude, you're
on a [__] list. You're going to get
perval October." And it didn't happen
because what happened in between then?
So, one guess is they were likely
coercing him to provide false statements
similar to Michael Cohen. Just tell us
your analysis of this statement he made.
>> I don't believe him. Okay, James. I
don't believe him. You know, I I watched
this video very closely. This seems
Well, I've come to a couple of
conclusions. This seems like a guy who's
intensely lonely. He's trying to win the
affe the affections of an attractive
woman. There's there's a fine line
between love and hate. He hates you,
>> but he loves me.
>> But I think maybe he loves you, too.
>> Have you come across characters like
this?
>> Oh, yeah. All the time.
>> All the time.
>> Yeah. And at the CIA, you're trained to
exploit them.
>> How so? How do you exploit them?
>> I'll give you an example. I was
instructed to recruit uh a senior Arab
diplomat one time. I met him for coffee
just to try to assess him. I immediately
assessed that he was gay. I reported
that to CIA headquarters. They told me
to pretend that I was gay and to pick
him up.
>> How do you assess if someone is is
homosexual?
>> You you just kind of feel it in your
gut.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> Um so so he's so he's uh a fine line
between love and hate. Um but a question
and and we'll move on from this subject
in a moment, but a question is
>> this individual got close to a lot of
people like he was on Tucker Carlson
show.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> you know 10 times or whatever it was. is
I mean I I this is on Fox News and
people like Charlie Kirk and myself
personally were blacklisted from Fox
News actually at the time funny enough
separate story he got close to Steve
Bannon at the war room he got close to
he's on the board of all these different
organizations and one of the questions
and and maybe this is a question I
should answer but you're you're a
subject matter expert you watched a
30-minute video you kind of have a a
character profile on the individual how
is he able to weasle his way to the top
of all these nos in the conservative
sphere in your estimation? Yeah, I
actually have to admit to some
admiration for that. Uh this is a guy
who is very arrogant. He is very uh much
a believer in his own abilities even if
he sort of believes too strongly in his
abilities. But he obviously appears to
be a guy who is good at stroking the
right people.
>> Okay.
>> And I think that's how he did it. You
know, it's it's not unusual, too, to
encounter somebody who is on a lot of
boards, is thrown off a lot of boards,
and then goes on to a lot of new boards
just because people get smart to him,
and they realize he's not all that he's
cracked up to be,
>> and they find new institutions that are
not wise to his shenanigans. That's
exactly right. Yeah. There's a We've all
encountered people. So, going back to
what you did at the CIA, you you
exploited in with the the ego and the
arrogance of this type of profile. How
did you do that? you you did it
brilliantly in this by by putting an
attractive woman in front of him.
Sometimes it really is as simple as
that. What you do there there's a
there's a cycle. We call it the asset
acquisition cycle of the CIA. Spot,
assess, develop, recruit.
>> So I spot this guy.
>> Um I assess his access to information
that I want. I develop him by making him
think that we're great friends
>> and I identify his vulnerabilities, his
weaknesses. In this case, just in a
quick 30 minute video, it's clear that
he has a weakness for an attractive
woman.
>> I think we all do, right? Is that is
that a commonality?
>> People do. Yeah. Especially for for
older men or men that might be a little
overweight or losing their hair. Yes.
>> Lonely,
>> right? Lonely. And uh and then you move
in for the kill.
>> So, when you worked at the CI, I mean,
I'm a I'm a journalist. So, my my
objective is the public's right to know.
Yes. We we we we we celebrate when we
get the story that we think is important
for the public. In your job, what was
your objective? Broadly speaking,
>> it was the White House's right to know.
>> The White House my former deputy
director, the guy that I worked for as
executive assistant, he had this mantra
and the mantra was the job of the CIA is
to recruit spies to steal secrets and to
analyze those secrets so that the
president can make the best informed
policy. It was as simple as that.
working on behalf of the government, the
executive branch of government,
specifically the commander-in-chief.
That's right.
>> Um because I always I always thought
that and I and I've and I have some
training from people that did what you
did. But it was very important for me to
distinguish what I do from what you do
because I'm not working on behalf of the
state. That's right.
>> Whereas whereas you you are. So in your
case, you were just when when you say um
what was that? Uh uh asset recruit.
>> Yes. Uh spot, assess, develop, recruit.
>> Spot, assess, develop, recruit. the
asset acquisition cycle
>> recruit either to get the the individual
to betray their country or simply give
you intel that you can relay.
>> Oh, both.
>> Or both.
>> Both. Yeah.
>> And in that case, were you able to get
the guy to betray his
>> We were always trained to not make the
final pitch unless you were 100% certain
they were going to say yes. And by then,
you had already gotten them to sort of
implicate%.
>> 100%. I never I made nine recruitments
over the course of my career
>> and I never had anybody say no.
>> You walk a fine line like in my business
when I go get someone on tape,
>> you know, the other thing that I don't
do and this is a fine line is is
blackmail because you have these people
on tape. I do. And and you could be very
evil with what I have. I don't I don't
do that.
>> No. No.
>> But in your in your field, you probably
it's part of being a spy.
>> You'd be surprised. Uh the answer really
is no because we have found over the
years that people don't really react to
that kind of coercion or pressure. You
want them to genuinely like you. You
want them to like you so much that
they're willing to commit treason for
you.
>> Yeah.
>> So you're seducing them.
>> That's that's probably the best the best
descriptive word. Yes.
>> And and I I mentioned that book Master
of Disguise by um I forgot the guy's
name that that did the the movie all
Argo or what?
>> Yeah. Oh, it's
>> Ben uh Ben Affleck played him in a movie
Argo.
>> Ben Affleck in Argo.
>> And And you've worn disguises in your
line of work.
>> Yeah. Many times. Every time there was a
walk-in to the American embassy,
wherever I happen to be stationed, you
have to wear disguises.
>> What type of disguises?
>> Usually it's as simple as a mustache, a
fake mustache and a wig. Um, back then I
didn't wear glasses, so I would put on
glasses. They were just frames with
clear glasses. But at one of my overseas
posts, we experimented with the first
ever bald head with a comb over. It took
them six weeks to place each hair one by
one by one and to get the the skin color
a perfect match with my own skin.
>> How how old are you?
>> Uh 61 now.
>> 61. And when did you start with the CIA?
How old were you?
>> I was 25.
There are there are there's a ven
diagram. I keep saying this between what
I do and what you do, but they're not
the same. And I'll go first.
>> They're parallel.
>> They're parallel. Well, there's there's
some overlap. I mean, we use aliases,
and I use disguises. People comment that
my disguises are completely ridiculous,
but they work a lot of the time. Is that
because people are just so full of
themselves? They're they're they're not
One of the things I just I I find out in
Washington DC, particularly DC, and I
was in Davos for the World Economic
Forum.
>> They're they're stuck in their own
little They're not really paying
attention to me.
>> They're they're having a they're
confessing to the ether.
>> Well, what is that? Why Why do people do
that?
>> That's arrogance. Arrogance. People love
to hear their own voices. People love to
sound not just to others but to
themselves that they are the leading
experts on an issue. They're insiders
and they want to show they want to prove
just how intelligent just how
well-connected they are.
>> And that's true for 90% of people.
>> Yeah. Just about
>> and in politics
>> 100%. You have to be a sociopath or a
narcissist to even want to enter
elective policy.
>> Or perhaps like people say, you know,
like someone like, you know, an
entrepreneur that that starts a company.
Maybe they're a little on the spectrum.
There's something off. But I mean that
as a compliment. Yes.
>> You have to either or you have to be
motiv motivated by some extreme form of
vengeance. Like there has to be
something wrong about you to do to do
this.
>> That's right. Well, I've said many times
on on podcasts that the CIA and I got
this from a CIA psychiatrist. The CIA
actively seeks to hire people with
sociopathic tendencies.
>> Sociopathic
>> they they don't want to hire sociopaths
because sociopaths have no conscience,
no ability to feel remorse and they blow
right through the polygraph because they
don't feel regret.
>> Wow. So what's a sociopathic tendency?
>> The sociopathic tendency is somebody who
is perfectly happy to operate in legal,
moral or ethical gray areas because of
the belief that we're the good guys.
I'll give you an example. I was leaving
Pakistan, my very last day in Pakistan,
and I was so looking forward to meeting
up with my fiance 24 hours later, and we
were going to go on vacation to uh Santa
Fe. 2 hours before I left the embassy, I
got a cable saying, "Don't come home. We
want you to go to this other country
instead, and we want you to meet up with
the team there. You're going to break
into a house, and you're going to plant
some hidden cameras." And I said,
"Okay." And I did.
>> You didn't object to this, or you just
Well, you followed your orders. You you
>> and I believed in the mission. We were
the good guys.
>> You were you have to believe you're the
good guys to do this, which requires a
little bit of sociopathic tendencies.
>> That's right.
>> You can't really question your your
orders in the military in any event,
right? You have to be trained.
>> And if headquarters said that this was a
bad person, a terrorist that we needed
to collect intelligence on, I was all
in. What's the difference between
Hollywood's depiction again I'll go
first here in answering my own question
Hollywood's depiction like Jason Bourne
and James Bond but that's kind of you
know ridiculous but my my my perception
of the big difference is the people
people I get thousands of people oh I
want to be an undercover for you the
hardest part for me is just the torture
of traveling I mean it is not fun to be
on a airplane ac overseas and sleeping
on the floor of a Portuguese airport on
a Saturday and hotel rooms all alone.
It's just hard work. That's the big
difference for me between the glamour
perception. But in your in your
business, in your line of work, what was
the difference between Hollywood's
depiction and what you do?
>> Hollywood's depiction. And I'll add by
saying I was the script adviser on the
Born Ultimatum. You were in addition to
a bunch of other CIA movies and and two
CIA related TV shows. Um we we try to
make sure that the scripts are are true
to life as best we can. But the the big
difference is what you see in a Born
movie is somebody's entire career packed
into one hour operation.
>> Two hours.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. There's a lot of hurry up and
wait. Surveillance is is just
>> soul crushing.
>> I see.
>> You sit there for hours, sometimes days,
just sitting there
>> and and peeing, urinating in a in a cup
or whatever. That actually happens.
>> Oh, yeah. You go to your bathroom,
>> your fake mustache is starting to peel
off
>> and Yeah. You're tired of the guy that
you're sitting with. That's a good
point.
>> I once I once sat
>> on, you know, the the lid of a toilet
for nine hours listening to a
conversation in an adjoining room as a
guy was being polygraphed.
>> Listening how so through
>> just just to see if he was going to lie
to you. No, I I just just through the
crack in the door just to see was he if
he was going to lie to the poligrapher
and the security officer that was in
there with him.
>> And you can't move on the toilet. You
can't shimmy. I I thought I was going to
faint after a while.
>> I've I've been there. Not not that
extreme, but I mean, this is a weird
anecdote, but urinating in in I've had
women in the in in the trunk of a car
urinate a woman in a cup because we
couldn't leave the car.
>> And the right people are not going to
complain about it. It's just part of the
job. It's the mission, right?
>> I I was being investigated for a
security clearance once and the FBI
agent that was investigating me said,
"Uh, have you ever been um arrested?"
And instinctively I said, "In the United
States." And she says, "What's that
supposed to mean?" And I said, "Oh, no,
no, no, no, no. I've never been
arrested." Thinking, "Oh, shit."
>> Yeah. I can't talk about those other
times.
>> Yeah. So, you've been in foreign you've
been in in jails and prisons overseas.
You've been through a lot of stuff.
>> Yeah. I've been through a lot of stuff.
>> And you can't talk about everything
you've been through, right?
>> But it's rare that you you see I don't
know how many of you there are out
there, but you you you talk a lot.
You're you're an outspoken person. Is
Yeah.
>> And that what what what
>> how did it come about to be that way?
You know, if you had Googled me before
December the 11th, 2007, you would have
found one entry and it was I sold one
house and bought another house and it
was in the Washington Post, you know,
little
>> public information thing. When I went
public over the CIA's torture program,
it exploded. And after the Obama
administration prosecuted me, I decided
that my mission in life was to tell the
truth and to be as vocal as I possibly
could be about government wrongdoing.
Even my my ex said, "Man, if if they
thought that arresting you was going to
silence you, they didn't know you at
all."
>> And I've embraced it.
>> That was over your whistleblowing on the
on the torture.
>> Yes.
>> So So So take us back to that that
moment. And this is important question
because I ask everybody who blows
whistles.
>> What really what made you do that? You
were indignant. Righteous indignation.
Take us back.
>> I wish I could tell you that, you know,
I took a position and I stood up and I
told them that wasn't it at all.
>> Mhm.
>> Um I didn't intend to blow the whistle,
but I got a call from Brian Ross at ABC
News in early December 2007.
>> 2007.
>> Yep.
um saying that he had a source who said
that I had tortured Abu Zuba. This was a
man that we thought was the number three
in al-Qaeda that I had led a raid in
Pakistan and captured. I said that was
absolutely untrue. I said I was the only
person who was kind to Abu Zuba. I've
never laid a hand on him or on any other
prisoner. I said your source is either
grossly mistaken or he's a liar. And
Brian said I didn't know this was an old
reporter's trick because I had never
spoken to a reporter before. He said,
"Well, you're welcome to come on the
show and defend yourself." Well, a
couple of days later, President Bush
gave a press conference in which he
looked directly into the camera and he
said, "We do not torture."
>> And I said to my wife, who was also a
senior CIA officer, I said, "He's a
bald-faced liar,
>> looking the American people in the in
the eye, and he's just lying to us." And
then two days later, it was a Friday,
Bush was walking out of the South
Portico of the White House to the
helicopter to fly to Camp David and a
reporter shouted a question about
torture and he stopped and he turned and
he said, "Well, if there is torture,
it's because of a rogue CIA officer."
And I told my wife,
>> Brian Ross' source is at the White House
>> and they're going to try to pin this on
me. I said, "I'm going to go public."
>> So I I called Brian Ross and I said,
"I'll give you your interview."
>> Wow.
>> And I decided just to tell the truth and
let the cards fall. And we have the
clip. Uh, Andrew, let's play the clip
from what John is talking about.
>> We had a group of folks at the agency
who were trained in what have been
reported in the press to be called
enhanced techniques. These enhanced
techniques included everything from what
was called an attention shake where you
grab the person by the lapels and shake
them all the way up to the other end
which was waterboarding.
>> And that was one of the techniques.
>> Waterboarding was one of the techniques.
Yes.
>> And was it used on Zeta?
>> It was.
>> Wow. Um,
I mean, I I I find this fascinating
because you you spoke out, you made this
incredibly difficult decision. Was it
was it because you wanted to write
wrongs? You you wanted to correct the
lies of the White House? I mean, what
was it?
>> You know, in my in my gut, I knew that
this was illegal. We have a we have a
law in this country called the Federal
Torture Act of 1946, which specifically
outlawed exactly the same techniques
that the CIA was using. We executed
Japanese soldiers in 1946 who had
waterboarded American PS. And then in
1968, in January of 1968, there was a
front page photograph uh on in the
Washington Post of an American soldier
waterboarding a Vietnamese North
Vietnamese uh prisoner.
>> The day that that photo was published,
the Secretary of Defense, Robert
McNamera, ordered an investigation. The
soldier was arrested. He was convicted
of torture and sent to to uh Levvenworth
for 20 years. Well, then in 2002, like
magic, it's all legal. Then the law
never changed. Congress never never uh
revoked it. They never amended it. We
changed and we just pretended that the
law didn't apply to us because we were
the good guys.
>> But most would Is it fair to say that
most CIA officers wouldn't do what you
did here?
>> Most would not.
>> Why not? Uh, you know, honestly, there
were some true believers, but for most
of the others, they just didn't want to
rock the boat, jeopardize their
pensions, you know, future promotions.
>> But you were willing to do that.
>> I was willing to do that.
>> So, what made you different than all the
others?
>> I don't know. I was raised in a church
going home, um, Catholic,
>> uh, Orthodox,
>> which is even more conservative than the
Catholics.
>> And, um,
I don't know. Right and wrong was always
clearly defined in my life. I see. I
mean, that's really the issue at hand in
our country, isn't it?
>> Because a lot of people don't want to
shake boats, rock the boat, lose their
money, lose their job, lose their
pension. No. And
>> and you know, funny thing, if I could
interrupt you for a second, was the the
minute that we began to to torture Abu
Zuba, I was the executive assistant to
the CIA's deputy director for
operations. So, I'm seeing the reporting
come from the secret site, and there are
doctors out there saying, "Whoa, I never
signed on for this. I took an oath to do
no harm. I'm coming home. I quit. I
resign. A secretary fainted when she
accidentally walked into the room while
they were torturing Abu Zuba. So I was
not the only person that was just
repulsed by this. Like when the
secretary fainted, what was was it like
zero dark 30? That kind of thing. Was it
worse? Was it What are we talking?
>> Well, I always maintained that there
were worse things than what what we saw
in Zero Dark 30. Worse things than water
boarding. There there were two there
were two techniques that I always
believed were worse. One was the cold
cell, which is when we chill a cell down
to 50° F.
>> Um, you chain the prisoner to the
ceiling with an eyebolt like this so he
can't get comfortable. He can't lay down
or kneel or sit and then he's naked and
then every hour a CIA officer goes into
the cell and throws a bucket of ice
water on him
>> every hour.
>> And we killed two people with that
technique.
>> Hypothermia.
>> And then you just bury him, you know,
behind the building. And then the other
one was uh sleep deprivation. Uh this
leaked around 2005
2004 and Don Rumsfeld, Secretary of
Defense famously said he didn't believe
there was such a thing as sleep
deprivation because he had a stand-up
desk in his office. He didn't even sit
down and he would work 24 hours, 36
hours without stopping. But we know from
the American Psychological Association
that people begin to lose their minds at
day seven with no sleep. They begin to
die of organ failure at day nine. And
the CIA was authorized to keep people
awake for as long as 12 days.
>> So it doesn't work. It's not pragmatic.
Did any of these methods of torture,
>> did they work?
>> No. Not in terms of of allowing us to
gather actionable intelligence. What
worked was the FBI's practice of just
engaging people in conversation. And um
I mean you and I could talk for five
hours. We've got it. We've got an hour
left. Um so many directions to go in
here with this line of questioning. um
my mind goes to the place where if you
or I are tortured, what techniques do
they teach us? Because we all have a
breaking point. Yeah.
>> And I like to say my price is my life,
right? You know, when they're, you know,
I one of my jokes is
>> I wish I had thought of it.
>> One of my everyone has a price and if
your price is your life, then that's
your price. Um but one of my thoughts is
well, I'm never going to tell you who my
confidential sources. You'll have to
waterboard. I always say that as a joke.
You have to waterboard me. What do they
teach you in your training if you're
tortured to not give up information?
It's the same thing that they taught
John McCain back in the in the day in
the 60s. Uh John McCain was being
tortured mercilessly and uh he was being
asked the names of uh the other men in
his unit. It was kind of an entrylevel
question
>> and so he gave them the names of all of
the members of the offensive line of the
1965 uh Green Bay Packers
>> and they said, "Good, good. You see, you
see how easy that was?" And then they
gave him a little bit of food and they
stopped torturing him. So listen,
eventually the person that you're
torturing is going to tell you what you
want.
>> That technique might not work today
because they'll Google,
>> right? They'll Google it. But but what
happens is the prisoner will give you so
much garbage
>> in addition to the real information. You
have to turn all of that over to an
analyst or a team of analysts. It's
going to take months for them to get
through it and then by then the bomb's
already gone.
>> I see. That's interesting. Okay. So you
you feed them a bunch of information to
get a little food. You give them
something. Even Khal Shake Muhammad
confessed to killing Daniel Pearl. We
knew for 100% certainty that he hadn't
killed Daniel Pearl,
>> but he confessed it just to get them to
stop torturing him.
>> Um, kind of going full circle because
you you this was Brian Ross on ABC News.
Yes. This is this is what 20 years ago?
19 years ago.
>> Yeah. 19 years ago.
>> Totally different. I guess
>> we all grow older in life. Um, I I guess
this it's what's fascinating to me and
you're on a the show called the show is
called The Price is My Life and I like
to get your thoughts on this is that we
need people to be willing to give up
something and and and you you you gave
up something. You went to you went to
prison.
>> I went to prison
>> for how long?
>> Uh 23 months
>> where
>> uh FCI Lorettto, Pennsylvania.
>> And was it a highsecurity prison?
>> It was a low security prison. At
sentencing, my lawyers asked the judge
to send me to a minimum security work
camp. Uh there are no no locks on the
doors, no bars on the windows. Most of
the guys work in town. There's a little
university there. Um the CIA was just
apopleleic that I was being sent to a
minimum security work camp. And so they
secretly asked the Justice Department to
bump me up. So I got to the prison. I
got to the camp and they said, "Oh, you
have to go across the street to the
prison and then they'll process you and
they'll walk you back over here." or so.
I went over over to the prison and they
cuffed me and started walking me around
to the back of the prison. I said, "No,
no, I'm supposed to be at the camp
across the street and the guard kind of
chroled and he says, "Not according to
my paperwork. You're not."
>> Took me four days to get access to a
phone and I called my attorney finally
and I said, "Hey, listen. They put me in
the actual prison with the pedophiles
and the mafia dons and the drug
kingpins. What do I do?"
>> And he said, "Oh my god." Well, he said,
"We could file a a motion, but it'll be
two years before we get a hearing.
You'll be home by then. He said, "Buddy,
I'm sorry. You're just going to have to
tough it out." And so I decided, you
know what? You've been in far worse
places than FCI Lorettto, Pennsylvania.
You're trained for this. And so I just
set out to handle it.
>> For how long?
>> Two years. Two.
>> Two years.
>> Mhm.
>> I didn't get one single day of halfway
house time. The CIA ensured that I did
as much time as I possibly could do.
>> Did you encounter any violence in the
prison? Did you did you
>> only violence that I initiated?
>> You initiated the violence.
>> But you know, one of the things they
taught us at the CIA was let others do
your dirty work. And that's what I did.
>> That's what you did.
>> I never ever got my hands dirty. Never.
>> Your your trade craft came in in handy
>> or did it. I was repeatedly called to
the lieutenant's office for
investigation. And you know, rule number
one at the CIA is admit nothing, deny
everything, make counter accusations.
>> That's kind of what reminds me a little
bit of of Trump's lawyer and what was
his name? Ray Ray Coin. Ray uh uh
Raycoin
Roy Con. Yeah, that's kind of rule one,
two, and three. Ad meant nothing, did
not always declare victory. Um so you
were you were locked up and you you
were, for lack of a better word,
manipulating other folks to do your
bidding so that you didn't have to get
your hands dirty.
>> That's exactly right. And I forged
strategic alliances, which I began on my
very first day there. So, uh, my my I
was in prison for an hour and, uh, the
only thing that the guard who processed
me told me, the only the only words that
he spoke directly to me were, "If
anybody comes into your cell uninvited,
that's an act of aggression." And I
said, "Great. Thanks. I'm here 40
minutes and I'm going to get my ass
kicked."
>> So, sure enough, an hour later, this
these two guys walked in. One had a
swastika tattoo that took up his entire
neck, went up onto his face. The other
one had [__] you tattooed on his
eyelids. Mhm.
>> And um and I jumped up and I put my fist
up and I said, "What do you want?" And
one of them said, "Are you the new guy?"
I said, "Yeah." So he said, "Uh, are you
a you a rat?" I said, "No, I'm not a
rat."
>> He said, "You a fag?" I said, "No, I'm
not a [__]
>> Are you a cho?" And I'm standing there
with my fist. I said, "I don't know what
that word means." Okay. I don't know
what that word.
>> And he says, "Chomo, child molester." I
said, "No, I'm not a child molester."
And he says, "Okay, you can sit with the
Aryans in the chow hall." And I'm like,
"Oh." Oh, he's just going to take your
word for these things.
>> I know, right? You have to show
paperwork, though. Eventually, you have
like a week to show the paperwork. So,
I'm like, "Okay, I guess I'm I'm with
the Aryans now." And then, you know, I
had similar experiences with the Nation
of Islam because I had defended human
rights and with the uh with the Mexicans
cuz one Mexican asked me to write his
appeal and I did and I didn't charge him
anything. So,
>> are you an attorney by trade?
>> No, but I how how hard could it be?
Right. So, I wrote the appeal and sent
it in and he lost. He was guilty.
>> So, so did they find out about your case
eventually? Oh, this guy was a CIA case
officer. They find all that out.
>> It was before I got there.
>> And what did they think about that?
>> Well, it depended on what faction you
were with. So, there was one guy, shout
out to Mark Lanzelotti, one of the
Italians, the Italians named Gambino,
Genevese, Lucesi, etc. He he saw in the
Sunday New York Times that I was going
to report to the prison on Thursday and
he took it upon himself to go to every
one of the Italians and say, "Listen,
there's a CIA guy coming here, but
there's a big difference between the CIA
and the FBI. the FBI is rats and cops
and the CIA protected us from the
Muslims.
>> And so they welcomed me with open arms.
They adopted me and I spent every waking
moment.
>> Give the audience some background. The
CIA protected um them from the Muslims.
>> Right. So in the in the post 911 world
when you boiled when you boiled the CIA
right down to its bare bones, it was it
was working against Iraq, working
against al-Qaeda, working against
Afghanistan. And that was good enough
for them. And then this rumor somehow
got started among the Aryans that I had
been a hitman for the CIA. And one of
them finally came up to me, an Aryan
Brotherhood guy, a dangerous guy, and he
said, "Is it true that you were a hitman
for the CIA?" And I was prepared for the
question. So I said, "Look, it was
wartime and we all did things we weren't
proud of."
>> And that just made everything in life
easy.
>> What did he say in response to that?
>> That was perfectly good with him.
>> He just accepted that. You kind of
thought through in your mind whatever
questions they would ask you.
>> I did and I was prepared for it.
>> Were you scared in
>> the only thing I was worried about was
the guards. The guard the guards are
crooked and they're violent. They're
corrupts. They're dangerous.
>> Yeah.
>> And is that's probably true. If it's
true in your case, it's probably true in
most cases.
>> Yeah, I think so.
>> Um, do you do you experience fear in the
way that most people do?
>> No.
>> You don't experience There's a
difference between fear and danger. You
understand danger.
>> Sure. one of one of the guys that I
worked with uh when I resigned, I was
leaving, they had a little going away
party for me and um and he came up to me
and he said, "I want to tell you how
much I've admired you over these years."
I said, "Oh, gez, thanks. It's such a
pleasure to work with you." He said,
"No, you're different than everybody
else." He said, "You're not afraid of
anything." And I said, "You know what? I
never really thought about it, but that
but that's true. I'm not. And I don't
know why."
>> That's highly unusual, isn't it?
>> That's unusual.
>> And so, a couple questions on the fear
thing. Has society gotten more afraid?
Are people more afraid than they were 30
years ago in your estimation?
>> Oh, I think so.
>> What caused that?
>> I think in large part 9/11. I think in
some part we've seen this political
split in our society where
we can't be friends anymore with people
with whom we disagree politically. And
that's nuts to me. It's nuts. But we're
at the point where if you've got
conservative friends or conservative
relatives, oh my god, it's it's a a
highway to, you know, militia membership
or Antifa. I'll give you an example. I
I've got a cousin, bonafideed war hero
from the Vietnam War. Multiple bronze
stars. He has the V for valor, purple
heart, the whole nine yards. And I
happen to be in Tampa uh to see him. And
so I said, "Hey, let me take you to
lunch." So I went picked him up at
lunch. And he says, "Oh, wait a minute.
before I could pull out. I forgot my
gun. So, he gets out of the car, goes
back to the garage, gets his 9mm, puts
it in the glove compartment of my rental
car. And I said I said, "Dude, what are
you doing? I'm I'm a convicted felon.
This is felon with a gun." And he says,
"Yeah, well, you never know when we're
going to run into Antifa." And he was
completely serious. And I said, "Put the
gun back in the garage. I can't take you
to a restaurant with a gun."
>> What felony did they get you on?
>> Uh, I violated the Intelligence
Identities Protection Act of 1982.
got a crime for everything, don't they?
Not espionage or anything like this.
>> No, no, no. They charged me with three
counts of espionage. I hadn't committed
espionage.
>> They charged you with espionage. And
this is in the which district in
Virginia.
>> This is in the Eastern District of
Virginia. The espionage court.
>> And that's what I'm saying. You can't
really get a fair judge there. In fact,
I hired I hired O.J. Simpson's jury
consultant.
>> You did?
>> He was the uncle of my best friend's
wife, and he agreed to wave his $10,000
a day fee and just do it because he was
a nice guy. So, so jury the jury pool or
the judges are more unfair.
>> The jury pool. Well, the judges the
judges you're not going to get a fair
trial.
>> You're not going to get
>> the judges are are No security defendant
has ever won a case in the Eastern
District of Virginia ever.
>> Why are the judges unfair?
>> Because literally all of them have been
prosecutors.
>> Literally all of them.
>> All of the federal judges
>> in the Eastern District of Virginia. Are
they are the federal judges in the
article 3 courts appointed regionally or
did they get appointed from all over?
They're all they're all prosecutors.
>> Oh, they're all prosecutors. I think a
study was done by ProPublica in 200 I'm
going to say 11 in which they said
something like 92% of federal judges had
been prosecutors.
>> Wow. In my case in EDVA,
>> uh we had this jury consultant, you
know, take a look at everything and he
said, "Look, if we were in any other
district in America, I would say let's
go for it. we're going to win at trial.
But your your jury is going to be people
from the CIA or with relatives or
friends at the CIA, the Defense
Department, uh Department of Homeland
Security, FBI, and Intelligence
Community Contractor.
>> The jury would make to be the And this
is called Vadier. And and you're a
criminal defendant. So you had 12 jurors
instead of nine. I was a civil defendant
three times and I've been in three jury
trials, all civil. So I went through the
voadier process a few times. I
understand with that most people don't
live through that.
>> Yeah.
>> So you did jury selection. In my case in
DC, I had a case in DC in District of
Columbia. You're in the you were in the
Eastern District of Virginia.
>> Yes.
>> And in one of my cases,
>> it's still going on. It's in the It's in
the DC circuit court of appeals actually
nine years later. But three years, four
years ago,
>> one of the jurors was asked by the
federal judge, "Have you ever heard of
James O'Keefe?" And he goes, "Oh, no.
I've never seen that man before." Like
obviously lying. And then he worked for
the Hillary Clinton campaign. The case
was about our investigation into Hillary
Clinton. And as he gets off the bench,
there's something called preempt
preemptary strikes where you run out of
them. So you can't cross-examine the
juror. And the judge has to take the
juror at his word. The juror walks,
looks at me, and winks as if to say, "I
lied and there's nothing you can do
about it, James."
>> Oh my god.
>> And it was one of the most It was one of
the most It was one of the darkest
moments. What was jury selection like in
your case? You said you consulted a
jury. get that far. Um, I was facing 45
years in prison and they they held they
held it at 45 years for 10 months. In
fact, one of the assistant US attorneys
who later became the assistant attorney
general for the criminal division in the
Biden administration, she said to me,
"Take a deal and you might live to meet
your grandchildren, Mr. Kuryaku." So, I
said, "I'm not going to do 45 minutes."
I told her. So, they they stuck to that
for 10 months. Then they came down to 10
years. take a plea to an espionage
charge, do 10 years. I said no. Then
eight years, no. And then five years,
no. And my lawyer, who was what the
Washington Post called a legal titan,
Plato Caceris, he said to me, you know,
I've been a lawyer in this town for 50
years, and I've never seen them come
down in time. Usually, if you say no to
10, they go to 12, 15, 20. I said, "Why
are they coming down?" He said, "Because
they have a [__] case, and they know
it's [__] and that's why we're going to
trial."
>> So, finally, they came down to five. I
said, "No." Then three and a half. and I
said no. And then they said, "Best and
final offer, three years." I stayed up
all night with my wife. We talked about
it literally all night and I said no.
>> So the lawyers were very upset with me.
They came to the house the next day.
Plato was the first one in the house and
he said, "You stupid son of a [__]
Take the deal." He said like that. The
second, Bob Trout, lovely like southern
gentleman, he said, "If you were my own
brother, I would beg you to take the
deal." And then the third attorney, the
I had 11 attorneys. the the third of the
big ones. Yeah, this was a big case.
>> How did you afford 11 attorneys?
>> I only paid six of them and I ended up
well I ended up filing for bankruptcy
because I owed them $1.15 million.
>> Always the lawyers. I want to return to
that. I want you to keep doing the
story. But
>> so Mark McDougall from Aken Gump and
Strauss. He said to me, he pulled me
aside and he said, "You know what your
problem is? Your problem is you think
this is about justice and it's not about
justice. It's about mitigating damage.
Take the deal."
>> M. What does that mean mitigating
damage? that if I screw around and go to
trial, and this is what I asked him. I
said, "Okay, I get it. But if I go to
trial and I'm convicted, what am I
seriously looking at?" And he said, "12
to 18 years. Take the deal." And so I
took a deal for two and a half years. I
did 23 months. I had five kids at home.
>> You have five children. I wanted this to
go at the time.
>> Let me think. This was 14 years ago. So
they were 1916
97 and one.
>> Well, good good math. 19th you range the
gamut. 1 7961 19 and and what are your
ch what did your what did your what do
your children think of all of this?
>> To tell you the truth uh three of the
five don't speak to me because of this.
>> Which part? Which part? I'm I'm a
criminal and having a a convicted felon
as a father holds them back in their
careers. I I have an unusual name. If
you Google them, I pop up.
>> I see. And so, you know, one is a bond
trader in in uh Chicago and and one is a
a an elementary school teacher in
Raleigh, North Carolina. They're
embarrassed by all this.
>> They're ambitious people,
>> and I stand in the way of that.
>> Did they get that from their mother or
from some other Okay. Okay. No, they got
it from their
>> um Well, in the O'Keefe family, I think
that they they would see through that.
I'm not a convicted felon. I'm a I'm a
convicted misdemean.
>> That's okay.
>> That's a story. Wear it like a badge of
honor.
>> Wear it. I I think things have So, this
was 19 years ago, right? Or
>> 2007. No, no, I was prosecuted. Well,
see, I blew the whistle during the Bush
administration.
>> But you But when was the sentence?
>> It was the Obama administration that
went after me. So, I was sentenced in in
20 January of 2013 and I went to prison
in February of 2013.
>> But the world has changed in 2025 and
26. It'd be a totally different dynamic
for
>> Oh my god. Listen, I always considered
myself to be a part of what I called the
libertarian left. Uh, and I've long been
a strong believer that the ideological
spectrum is not a straight line and
these types of people. The ideological
spectrum is a circle and it meets and
with the advent of the MAGA movement,
that's where I feel like I found an
ideological home.
>> Yes. Um, political realignment.
>> Yes.
>> You've you've had a political
realignment. You you said you were third
generation Democrat,
>> but that you left the party and the
actions by Obama and Brennan confirmed
that decision. By the way, what was the
guy?
>> I want to go to this, but the the um
your take on the uh not the guy, the the
court cases involving Snowden.
>> Yeah.
>> And um
>> Assange.
>> Assange. Just what's your 30 secondond
take on both of the
>> I believe that Ed Snowden's a bonafide
American hero. It is illegal. Not just
illegal, it's a part of NSA's charter
that it cannot spy on Americans. And in
fact, most of what it does is to spy on
Americans. We wouldn't know that had it
not been for Ed Snowden. Uh Julian
Assange. Julian's a a tough guy to like.
Uh he's a guy who's, you know, publicly
on the spectrum. Uh you just have to
accept it. But what he did was very
brave. The American people had the right
to know what the likes of Hillary
Clinton and uh and John Podesta were
saying and planning and doing in the
name of the American people. But did um
and you you probably don't know the
answer to this because you'd be making a
speculation, but in the criminal
affidavit or the uh indictment of
Assange, they alleged that he cooperated
with Manning or conspired with Manning
to hack into the thing. And we don't
know if he did or not.
>> No, he didn't do that. You don't think
he did?
>> No, I don't think he did it. In fact,
the only person who said that was a
convicted Icelandic pedophile who had
also been convicted of making false
statements. He went to the FBI uh agent
who was uh who was assigned to the
American embassy in Reikuic and offered
up all this false information in
exchange for money and then had to
retract all of it.
>> Is that was that in the indictment that
Icelandic
>> Oh, yeah. That's that that's where that
information came from.
>> So, he didn't probably conspire with
Assange. He played the role of a
journalist receiving the information.
>> That was exactly
>> I think the I know this because it's
very similar to my case with the FBI
because they alleged I stole a diary. I
never stole anything. But the Supreme
Court cases Nikki vivabber 2001, a
journalist can receive information that
was stolen as long as journalist plays
no part. So Assange in the indictment it
said I think it said curious eyes don't
run dry. He's telling Manning give feed
me more stuff.
>> Yeah.
>> So that's a very fine line.
>> It's a fine line.
>> It is in
>> but he never tasked Manning.
>> He never tasked Manning.
>> And that's what this Ziggy Thor Darson
alleged.
>> What was his name?
>> Ziggy Thor Darson. Ziggy Thor Ziggy Thor
Dawson worked worked with Assange in
some capacity or
>> he was in Assange's orbit for a year or
two um in in the Iceland office of
Wikileaks and then just decided hey I
can make this work for myself.
>> Um so so I mean and and uh Julian
Assange has really paid a price. I mean
away in a in a room in England for years
>> multiple suicide attempts. Yeah,
>> it was terrible. Um, and the guy, it was
Brennan and Hayden, one of the clap
clapper when asked under oath, "Do you
spy?" And he did this whole thing, which
for a spy to do, it's like the worst
tell ever in Congress. You know the
video I'm talking about. Oh, no, not
wittingly. I mean, what type of spy
behaves that way in a congressional
hearing, I guess, when you're guilty.
>> And you remember the question was was
whether he spied on Americans,
>> right?
>> And then he said no. Which
>> which is a crime? It was a lying.
>> It was lying. Was he lying under oath?
>> Lying under oath. But no but no one no
one's held accountable.
>> No. Okay, I want to go to your political
realignment, but I'm jumping around here
um because I'm there's so many things to
ask you. Why is nobody held accountable?
Yeah. You know, this is this is the
Washington of of the 21st century.
either you're in or you're not one of
the one of the swells who's in. And the
the the system, the swamp takes care of
its own. That's why you have somebody
like John Brennan who can commit felony
after felony after felony and literally
never pay a price. The swamp takes care
of its own. Let's let's unpack that.
>> Okay, so the Republicans have the the
the White House. Trump's in there. I I
support the president. I support what
he's doing to clean up. Mhm.
>> I support Doge. I support what Elon was
doing. The swamp takes care of its own.
But but but what happens? Like is it
that they is it they get lobbyed by the
bad guys? Do they take money legally? I
mean,
>> it's actually even more simple than
that.
>> Taking the CIA as an example because
it's the example that I know the best.
>> Presidents come and go every four years,
every eight years. If you're at the CIA,
especially if you're in the senior
intelligence service, you're going to be
there for 25, 30, 35 years. I worked
with one guy, a national intelligence
officer who was there for 42 years.
>> And, you know, presidents come and go,
and they're most likely not going to
fire you. Even though at the CIA, we
served at the at the pleasure of the
president, we didn't have we didn't have
the same protections from the Civil
Service Act that everybody else in
government did. But um if you don't like
this president, you just don't ignore
him. You ignore his orders. You know
he's going to be gone in three or four
years and then you just wait for the
next guy.
>> Mhm.
>> So it's just the incentives. It's just
that the the the incentives are I mean
just walk me through this.
>> Well, the biggest problem it's not just
the incentives. The biggest problem is
that there is really no congressional
oversight. There's just none, especially
in intelligence. the the intelligence
committees are no more than cheerleaders
for the CIA and the rest of the
intelligence community.
>> Well, I'll give you a real life example.
When I got out of prison, I was invited
to dinner at the Greek ambassador's
residence and I went there and Senator
Ron Weiden was one of the guests and he
walked up to me and he said, "Hey,
welcome home. We were really rooting for
you. We were pulling for you." I said,
"Come on, Senator." I said, "I expected
more, especially from you." He got very
angry and he says, "Look, it took
everything I had just to not lose my
security clearance."
>> And I said, "Oh, you're afraid of them."
>> Oh,
>> that's what it is. You're afraid of
them.
>> Afraid of losing his clearance or afraid
of what exactly?
>> Oh, I think on the first level, afraid
of losing his clearance. On the second
level, afraid of them maybe turning on
him and starting to look at him. And you
know, listen, there's this book, there's
this book called Three Felonies a Day by
Dr. Harvey Silverglate. He's a professor
of law at Harvard University. And he
says that we are so overcriminalized,
so overregulated in this country that
the average American on the average day
going about his or her normal business
commits three felonies every single day.
With the point being, if they want to
get you, they're going to get you.
>> Well, in my case, they made up felonies
that I didn't even commit. See, and then
there's that,
>> which is a whole other dark.
>> Yeah.
>> So, you're you're you're in the what was
the name of that congressman?
>> That was Senator Ron White.
>> Senator Ron Widen from is it is it
Oregon?
>> And and he got upset at you that you
weren't more grateful to him. Yeah.
>> For, you know,
>> for what? I have no idea.
>> Yeah. It's kind of strange. It it really
is the the issue, I would say, of our
time of today, of tomorrow, of this
year. and every I'm an investigative
reporter and I put out the stuff and
people but nothing happens to these
people. That's that's just how people
feel which you know
>> I I believe that exposure
>> you know Benjamin Franklin said I'd
rather have newspapers with no
government than government with no
newspapers. I believe exposure is the
accountability that that people see the
disinfectant that we need.
>> It's the disinfectant. But what the hell
is going on is the I don't know the
answer to this. It's it's and I think
you've answered it to a degree that the
swamp takes care of its own that the
administrative state is there for 42
years that that the senator is afraid of
his security being taken away. I I think
about this question and I to me it's
almost like
I I I don't know the the the incentives
are completely off. Like in other words,
my my hypothesis is if I hold a bad guy
accountable
>> in my life.
>> Let's say I I c I hold people
accountable every week. I catch people
on tape.
>> They admit to doing things they
shouldn't be doing.
>> They lose their contracts. They lose
their job. They
>> people get fired in my videos.
>> So as a result of that, they sue me.
>> Right.
>> Now it's your fault.
>> They Yeah. Now under a torsious theory
of damage and blah blah blah. Now, that
probably won't work in in a federal
court if I litigate it to to summary
judgement,
>> but that's what they do. So, I I get
>> I get pain inflicted upon me
>> for for exposing them, for doing the
right thing for reporting what they say,
for revealing it to the American people.
And you you you went through something
similar. You went to prison with really
bad ombres.
>> Yeah.
>> For speaking out against something that
appears to be unconstitutional. Is that
correct?
>> I agree. So the people that tell the
truth get punished.
>> Yes.
>> Um so my theory, tell me if this is
right or wrong, is that the people in
charge, the attorney general, the the
powers that be, don't don't go after the
bad guys because they will be punished
if they do that. Is that is that
correct?
>> That's exactly what my belief is. That's
my position. Yes.
>> Tell us more about that. Like how does
that like is it because they're going to
take away a security clearance? They're
going to you know not allow him run for
re-election? like is is that what it's
about?
>> I think it's it's even not as
straightforward as that. Um there's
there's this fear that you're not going
to be
an insider anymore. You're not going to
be a part of the the group, the click,
you know, who gets all the the great
secret inside information. There was
this brief period from 1975 to 1982
where the Senate Select Committee on
Intelligence and the House Permanent
Select Committee on Intelligence did
honest to God oversight, right? Where
the CIA, what years were those?
>> 75 to 82, where the CIA had to operate
within the confines of the law. And if
you don't like that the law puts
handcuffs on you, then change the law.
>> Right? We can all agree to disagree. and
if you disagree, sponsor legislation and
we can have that that debate. But then
starting around 1982 and and really
culminating in around 1995,
the oversight committees just decided to
give up. And on the one hand, it's
impossible for a staff of 60, 70, 80
people on Capitol Hill to oversee an
intelligence community of what 60,000
70,000 people. It's just not possible.
And so you pick and choose your battles
until you can't even do that anymore. I
think that's what we've seen binders of
classified things. They they bring you
into a skiff and you can't bring a phone
and
>> That's right.
>> It's like you know thousand congressman
was one congressman was telling me about
that. I was like whoa. Yeah.
>> And then hey what was what is that what
is that word that one word for that
secret operation and then they bring out
another binder just for that one.
>> Exactly. And then you have to sign a
secrecy agreement to open that binder.
>> That's insane.
>> That's wild.
>> Terrible. And do they get I mean the
general public assumes that they get
compromat they get compromising material
on all these politicians. Is that does
that happen?
>> You know I've always been of the belief
that yeah that was true uh at the FBI.
That wasn't my experience at the CIA
just because they don't have the
wherewithal to do it domestically. I
will say though that my first boss now
this is dated
>> but my first boss told me that his first
job at the CIA was as an intern. He was
a grad fellow in the um office of um
what was it called? Um counter
intelligence.
>> And on his first day, he went in there
and there was an entire wall just of
file folders. And the secretary told
him, "You might find yourself to be the
only person in the office once or twice.
Whatever you do, don't look at those
files." And he said, "Well, of course,
you know, the minute that he's the only
person in the office, he went and looked
at the files and every single one of
those files was on an American citizen."
>> Whoa.
>> Mhm.
>> That was in the CIA. Guys said that.
That was a dumb thing for him to say.
Don't look at that. Don't look at that.
It's something that a spy shouldn't say.
>> But yeah, to answer your question, I I
believe that that compromat is something
that the FBI and God knows the stories
from Jay. Edgar Hoover, he was
collecting that stuff from the 1920s.
>> Yeah. I when I was raided by the FBI, I
I'm I'm also don't consider myself a
particularly fearful person. But what
struck me when they raided me, this is
in 2020, 2021, they got secret warrants
against me to spy on my newsroom, which
is its own constitutional crisis. the
attorney general expressly forbids it,
blah blah blah. The two two parts of
fear struck me when they did that to me.
Number one, it was like you said you you
said um they enforced the law between 75
and 82. It was the breakdown of the law
itself that there was no the concept of
justice is proportional were all equal
before the law. The law means something.
But when words ceased to have meaning
when when Merrick Garland can say you
cannot raid a newsroom and then raid a
newsroom.
>> Yeah.
>> It became like a animal farm. all all
animals are equal, but some are more
equal than others. That's when the fear
set into me. I was like, whoa,
>> this is a postconstitutional
dynamic. And the second thing that
really hit me hard, and again, I'm being
very vulnerable for the audience to give
them some background into what you're
saying
>> was after the raid, um, I had nothing in
my apartment except books and clothes.
They were looking for contraband,
looking for weapons, and I was like, are
they putting child porn in my drawer?
Are they putting cocaine? and that my
mind went to went to places I didn't I
didn't want it to go. And I never felt
that before. And I was I was totally I
mean I mean this sincerely. I was
totally overcome by a paralysis of fear.
>> Oh my god. Yes.
>> Have you ever been there?
>> Yes. And I've actually written about
exactly that. after my case, which
Donald Trump's first US attorney in Utah
called the Democratic Party's template
for Lafair.
Um, there was a a series of four or five
whistleblower cases where, like magic,
child pornography was found on every one
of these computers.
>> And I wrote this piece. I said, "Isn't
that a strange coincidence that child
porn is always on the whistleblowers uh
computers?" And in fact, there was one
whistleblower uh from the US Army who
said, "I never had any child pornography
on my computer." And then when the judge
demanded to see the pornography that was
pulled off the computer, the prosecution
couldn't produce it.
>> So yeah, that's a great fear of mine and
I think it's something that all
Americans should fear. again, if they
want to get you, they're going to get
you. Has that changed? Is the dynamic
changed present day? And I and I've got
about 15 minutes left with you. I want
to go to Epstein. Has the dynamic
changed in that the Elon Musk's purchase
of X, the sort of populist social media
movements that we're seeing
>> that it's like, come on. It's like,
remember the old 60 Minutes Mike Wallace
question? Oh, come on. There's child
porn on the journalist phone. Or is it
still a huge threat? No, I think it's I
think it's significantly better under
Donald Trump.
>> Yeah, significantly better.
>> Let's talk about Jeff Epstein. And
you've you've talked about this on so
many podcasts. I'm going to try to ask
you questions you haven't been asked.
And I'm going to start by
>> talking about Andrew, if we could pull
up the clips
>> specifically on the CIA. By the way, we
have two pieces of footage from
investigations that we've done from
individuals who have claimed they work
with or for the CI.
>> I've seen them.
>> You've seen the guy. Remember the guy
that was fired and in Langley for saying
he withheld information from Trump,
which by the way, I went to Langley to
do an on camera and people were
>> Well, I was on the the the highway
outside the building. I forget the name
of the road.
>> Yeah. Dolly Madison Highway.
>> Yeah. That and I was standing as close
as I could with the office. If you set
foot two feet that way, we'll arrest
you. And as people were driving out of
of the building, they actually rolled
down the keep going, O'Keefe. The FBI
wouldn't do that. No, the FBI wouldn't
do that.
>> The FBI wouldn't do that. And and I
think it was Congressman Nunez who said
that, and this is a broad
generalization, but I've heard this from
a number of conservatives, that
generally speaking, this is in 2023 and
24, that the FBI was more corrupt than
this the CIA. That that's the that's the
>> I always believed that. And in fact,
since my conviction, um, I've received
emails from three of the FBI agents
involved in my case apologizing for
targeting me and prosecuting me. They
said that they were ordered to do so.
>> Yeah.
>> And there was nothing they could do.
>> Following order. Well, there is
something they could do. They could
resign.
>> They could resign,
>> but they're not they don't choose to do
that.
>> See, again, it's the same at the CIA.
You don't want to rock the boat. You
don't want to jeopardize.
>> By and large, the the the I hate to use
this term. It's a it's a not a correct
uh term of art, but the rank and file.
>> Yes. of the CIA. I would generally good
people.
>> Yeah.
>> 80% or whatever.
>> Patriotic, smart, hardworking people who
want to do nothing more than to serve
the American people.
>> So, let's go to this uh clip from this
is Glenn Prager on an airplane. We
recorded this earlier this year speaking
about Epstein and he works with or for
the FBI interviewing the Epstein
victims. Glenn Prager, go ahead. A CIA.
Go ahead. It's not talked about yet, but
it soon come out that he was a CIA.
>> He was a CIA.
>> He was a CIA. I think he's protecting a
lot of other people. It's not He's not
protecting himself cuz there's nothing
there, but he's protecting a lot of
people because Trump's now saying it's a
hoax of the case like a hoax or
something. I mean,
>> you know, it's not a hoax. He's been on
the plane, you know, many times.
>> It's just he was never on the plane with
the kids.
>> I've seen the itinerary and and I've
interviewed all the victims. There's
never been incidents where Trump was on
a plane with these kids.
>> Mhm. occurred.
But that can't be said for Clinton and
it can't be said for others while the
Clintons.
>> And we have another clip where Prager
talks about Epstein being um was it was
Israel something comment he made working
with Israel working for Israel. Uh but
in any event he talks about um I guess
first your reaction to that just
watching that this is a guy just some
context. is Glenn Prager interviewed the
victims in Palm Beach County uh for the
Department of Justice.
>> On what he thinks is the case. What's
your perspective?
>> Yeah, I I think that most Americans who
have followed this story assumed that
that was the case. And now that we've
had this trunch of 3 million more
documents, it's pretty well proven it.
>> And and have you been going through
those documents? any any highlights, any
pullaways that you headlines that you've
come across?
>> There's something that's been very very
intriguing to me. The former Obama White
House counsel, Katherine Rumler, who's
now the general counsel for Goldman
Sachs, making probably more money than
she can count, uh, repeatedly repeatedly
tried to get, uh, CIA director John
Brennan to have lunch with Jeffrey
Epste. She and Epstein apparently were
very close. That wasn't necessarily new,
but uh there was one email that was new
where she emailed Epstein and said, "CIA
director John Brennan gave me the CIA's
highest honor this morning." Pretty
cool, huh? Or pretty neat, huh? And um
and then when Epstein was going to be in
Washington, she repeatedly went back to
him saying, "Let me set up a lunch with
John Brennan. You're going to like John
Brennan. Let me set up this lunch with
John Brennan." We don't know if they
ended up having lunch, but she was
working very hard to get John Brennan
together with Jeffrey Epste.
>> Why?
>> Oh, I've gone through so many of these
documents. It's it's it's
100% fact now that that Epstein was
working for the Israelis, but he doesn't
appear to just have been an Israeli
access agent. It looks like he had sort
of offered himself up to the CIA, to
MI6, to MI5, to maybe the Germans. there
there could have been other services as
well. And then we learned what just a
few days ago
>> that his attorneys actually sought
confirmation from the CIA and from the
National Security Council that Epstein
was acting as an informant.
>> Access agent to the to the foreign
interest.
>> Yes.
>> An epste is an informant and an access
agent to the foreign interest the same
thing or different.
>> Uh
there are minor differences. The the
point that I've been making is that
if you're a foreign intelligence
service, let's say in this case you're
the you're the Mossad, you're not going
to recruit Bill Clinton or Prince
Andrew, you're not going to recruit Bill
Gates. So you do the next best thing.
You recruit somebody who has access to
them and who these guys trust. And then
if you have a little compromise hanging
over their heads at the same time,
that's even better.
>> So we we'll get to we'll get to the
Israel thing in a minute because I mean
I mean I'm I'm going to be honest with
you. This is a this is a hot this is a
hot button. This is a hot topic. Charlie
Kirk, close friend. He was a friend with
a lot of people, but
>> I went to the Turning Point thing in in
July and Tucker was on stage and said
the thing and
>> it really upset a lot of people. It
upset a lot of donors to the
conservative movement. And I'm I'm
trying to be fair. I'm trying to be
factual. So, how do you know with 100%
certainty that Epste was MSAD as a fact?
>> How do you know that? I think that the
documents, there are too many documents
talking about too many incidents of
contact with senior Israeli military and
intelligence leaders to come to any
other conclusion. I happen to be on the
Pierce Morgan show a couple of months
ago. Uh I Scott Horton and I were on one
side, Alan Dersowitz and Danny Ayalon
were on the other side and um and I said
factually the Israeli spy on the United
States.
>> It's a fact, right? Jonathan Pard was
not an anomaly. The FBI will tell you
that there are at least 187 undeclared
Israeli intelligence officers spread all
across the United States stealing our
defense secrets, but they're Israelis
and we're close to the Israelis and so
we just pretend that that's not a
problem. Durowitz practically had a
stroke when I said it and said first
that that Epstein was not uh an Israeli
access agent. That if he had been he
said I was his lawyer. If he had been
working for the Israelis, I could have
gone to the White House and I could have
gotten him a more favorable sentence.
>> There there are documents in this in
this trunch of of three million uh
emails or what what as specifically as
you can. What what facts or documents or
exhibits or that that that show that
connection to Israel? I mean, this guy
says it. Prager Prager in the video says
it, but you know, it's it's hearsay. We
don't know if it we I can't verify what
the
>> guy in the FBI is saying is true or
false. But what documents have you seen?
The documents I've seen are documents
where he's telling, for example, um,
Prime Minister Ahoud Barack, former
Prime Minister Ahoud Barack, that he's
secured documents from the likes of
Peter Mandlesson, uh, and Prince Andrew.
We just learned this what, yesterday,
day before yesterday, Peter Mand, the
former uh, former British ambassador of
the United States that he has then sent
to the Israelis.
>> Um, I know I know we got to go, but I
want to spend another I want to show the
other two clips, Andrew, of the of the
Epstein footage and get John's reaction.
Uh, let's go to Attorney General Pam
Bondi. Attorney General of the United
States. This is this is footage that we
broke in May of this year and it's been
regoing viral now. So, if we could pull
that clip up just for some context while
we're getting that clip. The attorney
general is in a restaurant. Pause the
clip. The attorney general who's in a
restaurant and I don't I don't send
people out to do this. Sometimes people
send me stuff.
>> Oh, that's fun.
>> Or they say, "Hey, I'm in a position
where I can record this."
>> Um, and I and this is a tough one for me
because I don't want to You know, it's
this is a tough one to to whether we
publish this. And then Bondie went to
the White House and said what she was
caught on the video saying, "Play the
footage in a restaurant in DC from May
of 2025.
>> Files are going to get released."
>> Um, we hope soon.
>> Okay. Any dates?
>> No. You know what it is? There are tens
of thousands of videos and it's all with
little kids. So, they have to go through
every one. There are tens of thousands
of videos with little kids. Now, was it
Cash or or Blanch or someone said
recently, "Oh, there's no there's no
there's no play the comparison. Play the
other one of the other statement. I want
to get John's reaction." This is the
latest statement from Department.
>> There are tens of thousands of videos
with children or child porn. If there
was a video of some guy committing
felonies on an island and I'm in charge,
don't you think you'd see it?
>> All right. So, that was an interesting
What are your thoughts on the child the
children and the child porn and all
that?
>> First of all, there's no in my mind
there's no more horrible crime that
exists than a crime on a child. Um, I I
would like to think that Pam Bondi was
speaking off the cuff and was
talking about what she expected to
learn, expected to see. I'm trying to
give her the benefit of the doubt here.
Um, I really believe that Cash Patel is
telling us the truth when he says
>> if there was any evidence of a crime, by
God, he would be the guy to demand that
it be prosecuted. Um, that's why I
celebrated his appointment as as FBI
director because we we needed somebody
who's going to tear the place down to
the bare step and rebuild it. I think
he's having a tough time.
>> I think he's facing a lot of headwinds
and I think that he would tell you that
he has not accomplished what he thought
he could accomplish.
>> Is that due to the bureaucracy? I think
so. Yeah. I I I say that if if you
appointed Jesus Well, Jesus can walk on
water, so maybe that's a bad metaphor,
but it's tough. It's a tough job.
>> It's a tough job.
>> So, how do you think Pam Bondi is doing?
I like Pam Bondi and I think she means
well, but I don't think she's
accomplished as much as most of us
expected she would have accomplished by
now.
>> So she so she could have been speaking
off the cuff like many subjects do.
>> I really believe that
>> it is a little the question is should
the attorney general of the United
States be
>> sharing all this with a stranger in a in
a in a coffee shop? is that that there
are questions about the discernment and
the judgment of the chief law
enforcement officer of the Department of
Justice there. And then uh do we have
any other clips from from Epstein team?
>> Schnit. One one more. One more. This is
Schnit talking about um Gelain Maxwell
and the deal or the alleged secret deal
that she got. Let's play this guy who
was fired from the Department of Justice
after we recorded this.
>> Yeah. and also indulge
>> got transferred to a minimum security
prison too recently
>> which is against BP policy because she's
she's a convicted sex
>> and they're not supposed to get in
security prison which is an interesting
>> detail because she's getting a benefit
which means
>> they're offering her something to keep
>> transfer to a minimum security prison in
exchange for a deal. Your thoughts on
the Maxwell dynamic?
>> Yeah, I've written about this too. It is
absolutely anathema to BOP uh regulation
to allow a child sex offender to be
anywhere near a minimum security prison.
They can't be in maximum or medium
because they'll be killed there.
>> They can't be in minimum because they
can just walk away
>> and have access to a child again. They
have to be in a low security prison,
which is where she was
>> until her transfer was ordered.
Something I just have no understanding
of.
>> Do you believe that what that man said
is probably true?
>> Yeah. Yeah. To keep her mouth shut.
>> I think it I think it is.
>> And and and and again, I keep going keep
going back to accountability, but people
are demanding to know why weren't they
arresting anybody as it pertains to
Epstein. Why?
>> You know, I hate to say it. It's it the
simplest uh reason I think is the
correct one. The statute of limitations
on just about all of these crimes has
expired or
>> including against was it five years for
rape?
>> Five years. Five five unless you can you
can prove an ongoing conspiracy in which
case the statute of limitations would
reset itself every day.
>> Well, that's what the guy said in our
video la last week. The FBI guess said
they'll run the statute out. There'll be
a different president. He was just being
honest.
>> Yeah, he was being honest.
>> They fired him for being honest.
>> There it is. That's Washington. This is
>> Harry Truman said, "If you want a friend
in Washington, buy a dog."
>> I mean, it's almost true of human
nature, isn't it?
>> They fire you for being honest and the
child rapists go free. That's right.
>> And it's not necessarily, you know, I'm
just, this is my commentary. I don't
know if it's Cash's fault. I I I like
Cash. I've met Cash. I don't think
Bondie's a I I don't I don't actually
can't make a comment on on her. I've met
her once at a dinner. I I don't know if
it's the individual. I think it's the
nature of humanity, human nature.
>> I I think you're right.
>> Bureaucracy.
>> I think you're right.
>> So, in many ways, what you're fighting
against and what I'm fighting against
appears to be human nature itself.
>> And that's why it's such a tough fight.
>> It is. It is. It's It's a difficult
fight. and and the American
republic, the American experiment, we
have a very unique framework because we
have a by camera legislature and
separation of powers. Um, this is a very
big question I'm asking you, but are we
at the end of the rope for the American
experiment? You know what? As things
stand today, I think actually that we
are. I hate to say that, but there's
going to have to be a major
constitutional reset where the
legislative and and judicial branches of
government reassert their co-equal
authorities.
Otherwise, you know, we're we're kind of
devolving into into chaos.
>> Factions like like the Federalist
Papers. I think is that what you mean?
Like mobs?
>> Yeah, I do. I think so.
>> Like in the Minnesota you saw in the
agitation and and and I hate to ask
predict the future questions. I don't
answer them. But I am going to ask you a
predict the future question. Are we
looking at like a few years? Is it the
next election? Like what's going to
happen?
>> No, I think this is an incremental
process. I really do. I I don't think
it's going to be revolutionary in any
way. I think it it'll be evolutionary.
It'll continue to get worse, but it it's
not just going to explode. I don't think
we're seeing 1968, 1969 all over again,
>> but I think we're getting there
incrementally. Well, what strikes me is
the political prosecutions because they
go after all the Republicans and now
Trump's kind of attempting with Lemon
and these others, but I don't know if
there I don't I don't know if those
cases are going to are going to go
anywhere and Biden raided my newsroom
and that was dropped because that there
wasn't even a colorable crime, right?
But it is there going to be a dant like
where both sides or is it just going to
be like Brazil these guys get in power
and they go to prison? What's your
what's your prediction?
>> We're going to have to back away from
that. It's it's it's certain death for
the system. It really is because it's
only going to get worse unless the two
sides back off.
>> And we really have to be able to believe
in the judiciary again. I
>> I think we've lost faith in our
institutions. Everyone asks which which
party appointed the judge which is
completely
>> the first question
>> and I mean I I reject the premise. I
mean and and some article 3 courts are
not corrupt. I I I federal judges is my
opinion. probably the least corrupt
thing I've seen I've seen a lot as of
you. There's still is, for example, the
First Amendment is still generally
upheld in article 3 courts. They haven't
taken that away yet.
>> That's right.
>> But you got to litigate. You know who
stands to gain from all the political
prosecutions is the lawyers.
>> Yeah.
>> They said 1.1 million.
>> 1.15 million is what I still owe.
>> You still owe that?
>> Yeah.
>> And in our case, yeah, it's 25% of our
budget. The process is the punishment.
>> Well, the process is the punishment.
>> We're out of time and I could talk to
you for five more hours. fun. Is there
any closing comments you have about any
of what we've talked about or anything
you like?
>> Well, like you and I were talking about
just before we we started filming in our
guts. We know what the right thing to do
is. Always trust your gut.
>> Trust your gut.
>> Yeah. Your children are going to be
proud of you and you'll be able to sleep
at night. Sometimes it's hard. It's hard
for even if we know the right thing to
to How How do you trust How do you know
what is your gut? How do you How do you
know what that is? That sensation? You
know, I I've I've always believed that
that human nature is such that
intellectually we know what the right
thing to do is, even if we don't always
do the right thing because because it's
you maybe it's easier to do the wrong
thing, maybe you get a temporary
benefit. Uh but deep down we really know
what the right thing to do is. And I
think that even when it harms us
personally, I've been ruined. I I went
bankrupt. friends and family members
walked away from me. I'm unemployable. I
I have to work for myself essentially,
but I like my life and I respect myself.
And I think for all of us, that's really
what it comes down to.
>> Do you find that people just one follow
question to that that people you're you
hold a mirror up to the other guys who
didn't make the difficult decisions that
you made, therefore they kind of resent
you or they hate you because you have
the balls to do something they didn't.
>> I get that. I the day after I blew the
whistle, a a retired deputy director of
the CIA emailed me and he said, "You've
chosen a difficult road. I only wish I
had had the guts to do it myself.
>> I only wish."
>> Mhm.
>> Or people will say to you, "I can't do
what you do."
>> And your response is, "Yeah, you you
could."
>> Everybody could do what I did.
>> Everybody could, but they choose
>> you make a decision not to.
>> I don't know if we can save the country
unless people do what you do.
>> Thank you.
>> As hard as it is. you.
>> It's, by the way, this is hard.
>> It is hard.
>> This is This is brutal.
>> Mhm.
>> Brutal.
I don't mean to make a joke, but it's
like Shakespeare said, "Put all the
lawyers at the bottom of the ocean." I
don't I mean, I'm I'm I'm sorry, but I'm
not sorry. They profit off corruption
and human suffering.
>> And I'm trying to get lawyers hired
here. And if you're watching and you
want to work as a as a general counsel,
I will pay we'll pay you a quart million
dollars a year, $300,000 a year. But
you're still going to have to take a pay
cut from that $1,000 an hour. It's all
about greed, isn't it?
>> Yeah.
>> And I could have had a life where I
where I made a million dollars a year
using my talents.
It's it's it's it's the thing that gets
me. It's the betrayal of the good people
that do nothing. The good people that do
nothing. All that is required for the
triumph of evil is for good people. I'm
not angry at the evil. I'm angry at the
good who do nothing. That's right. Do
you feel the same way?
>> I do 100%. That's how I feel every